<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cupids Alley | Phil Cooper-King]]></title>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/categories/cupids-alley/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-16T21:42:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phil CK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global Game Jam 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2013/02/01/global-game-jam-13/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T20:54:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2013/02/01/global-game-jam-13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So a few of us decided to jump into the <a href="http://globalgamejam.org/">Global Game Jam 2013</a>, Our Uni (<a href="http://www.abertay.ac.uk">Abertay</a>) was one of the venues in <a href="http://www.scottishgamejam.org/">Scotland</a>. The theme was a <a href="http://globalgamejam.org/news/2013/01/26/ggj13-theme">heart beat</a>, after a few different ideas we settled on the idea of Cupid going on a bloody rampage, I think this is what happens when you are sleep deprived.</p>

<p>This was the result of our hard work.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/61953421" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Something I noted was our 'progress' was utterly dreadful. I've done a few 48 hour competitions and I'm generally the first to suggest having constant breaks eat right and sleep lots. This time though all that went out the window, I was having to commute to the venue as I don't live in the same city, and Sunday trains are very limited. So I made the decision just to stay at the venue and try and catch some sleep on a couch. Really there was a good atmosphere in the venue which lead to people not sleeping much. Looking back at our progress we could have made the same game even if we went home and had a good long sleep.</p>

<p>I know its nothing 'new' but in an industry that almost prides itself on 'crunch' you have to wonder if really there is <a href="http://www.lindsredding.com/2012/03/11/a-overdue-lesson-in-perspective/">any point</a> to it at all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
