<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Graphics | Phil Cooper-King]]></title>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/categories/graphics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-24T19:41:09+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phil CK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual Texture]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/10/24/virtual-texture/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T16:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/10/24/virtual-texture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So for my Honors project I've decided on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MegaTexture#Virtual_texturing" title="Virtual Texture">virtual textures</a>, its a rather scary term (at least to me) but it actually has a lot in common with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_memory" title="Virtual Memory">virtual memory</a>, and in most cases you can simply swap the word 'memory' with 'texture' to get an idea how it works.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>VTM systems are more flexible and mimic the virtual memory management of the OS:</p><footer><strong>Matthäus G Chajdas et al</strong> <cite>GPU Pro - Virtual Texturing 101</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>That make me feel a little easier about topic. So what we have is an actual texture on a disc which contains all the data that we need but to much to squeeze into the GPU. A texture on the GPU which contains all the data that we currently need. And a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Page_table" title="Page Table">page table</a> thats lets us find out where the bit of texture is that we are looking for, as it might not be in the same place when we come back to (Hence the virtual bit).</p>

<p>Rage has some nice visualisations you can turn on. On the left its showing the page numbers, and on the right its show the mip levels its rendering at. Green being the lowest, red highest.</p>

<p><img src="/post_images/Honors/rage_vis.jpg"></p>

<p>Well thats all very nice and all, but what does it actually give us? It would allow artists to create completely unique (ie. no repeating textures) texture detail over a very large area, it should also reduce our memory footprint as we are only loading up the data we need when we need it.</p>

<p>With all things though this doesn't come free. The first problem is its slow to hit the disc for data. When you are trying to load up data you could get a lot of texture popping. That isn't really desirable however it is almost inevitable with this kind of solution, there are some tricks to reduce it but it comes down to the usual game of trying to balance things out. Another problem (on the development side not runtime) is hardware <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bilinear_filtering" title="Bilinear filtering">filtering</a>. When the hardware is doing a bilinear filtering it will be using data from its neighboring texels, which in this case could be an entirely different texture.</p>

<p>There is really good video on Virtual textures it over at <a href="http://silverspaceship.com/src/svt/" title="Silver Spaceship">silverspaceship.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Honors Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/honors-project/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T18:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/honors-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The topic for my honors project was a hard decision. The two main contenders were <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deferred_shading#Deferred_lighting" title="Deferred Lighting">deferred lighting</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MegaTexture#Virtual_texturing" title="Virtual Texturing">virtual texturing</a>, with a visual programming language and VR headsets taking the runners up topics. In the end I chose virtual texturing. Something that Rage used to generate some very petty scenes, and some very interesting texture popping.</p>

<p><img src="/post_images/Honors/rage.jpg" title="'Rage'" ></p>

<p>The basic idea is that you create a massive texture file, in Rages case I believe they could be up to 128,000 x 128,000 pixels then just stream off the hard-drive (or disc) the information you need based on your position in the world.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Regardless of how much detail its texture might contain, you cannot display more texels than the screen has pixels.</p><footer><strong>Ben Garney</strong> <cite>Game Programming Gems 7 - Clipmapping</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The motivation is an old one, textures in the distance need not have as much detail in them as textures closer to the camera. But the two texture files might take up the same space on the GPU. So if we can stream in the amount of information when we need it we can save our-selfs a lot of memory.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Playstation 2 FishEye]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/02/02/ps2-fisheye/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-02T19:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/02/02/ps2-fisheye</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were tasked with creating a 'visual effect' for the PS2 using its VCL code. This was quite interesting, I thought I'd found all the ways to crash a PS2, then another one comes along. Get your VCL code wrong, and boom!</p>

<p>I ended up thinking of it as a vertex shader, and created a fish eye type effect. Its not a true fish eye effect because I am actually moving the vertices which means you can peek around corners so to speak.</p>

<p>[pic in-coming]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texture Importers]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/05/02/texture-importer/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T19:58:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/05/02/texture-importer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote these importers (Targa and Bitmap) for OpenGL (Well any API I guess), I originally wrote these for the PS2 because the importer we were given was such a pain to use.</p>

<p><img src="/post_images/SideProjects/texture_loader.png" title="'textures'" ></p>

<p>The Targa was interesting as it has quite a few features in the file spec, the fact you can orientate the image when storing to disc any way you want I found a little unnecessary. Code can be gotten here if you are interested, they are pretty much complete, although they don’t support RLE compression.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGL Tardis]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/opengl-tardis/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T19:59:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/opengl-tardis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was my second year coursework for Graphics Programming. I was very disappointed in the module as a whole - I struggle to see the benefit of learning the fixed function pipeline any more, along with every feature of OpenGL that no longer exists. The module felt like it was put together by somebody who didn't care, and the claim that we would learn the theory of graphic programming turned out to be marketing speak, for learning next to nothing useful.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/22864220" width="500" height="370" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Disappointment of the module aside I was happy enough with outcome of my coursework, I created the models (but not the textures) in <a href="http://www.blender.org/" title="Blender">Blender</a>, and used <a href="http://chumbalum.swissquake.ch/" title="Milkshape">Milkshape</a> to import them (the only model loader I had at the time was a Milkshape one). Milkshape kept flipping the normals on me for some reason, the solution was rather mental, I turned them inside out in Blender and Milkshape flipped them back around.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
