<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Coursework | Phil Cooper-King]]></title>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/categories/coursework/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-10T16:26:54+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phil CK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Honors Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/honors-project/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T18:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/honors-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The topic for my honors project was a hard decision. The two main contenders were <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deferred_shading#Deferred_lighting" title="Deferred Lighting">deferred lighting</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MegaTexture#Virtual_texturing" title="Virtual Texturing">virtual texturing</a>, with a visual programming language and VR headsets taking the runners up topics. In the end I chose virtual texturing. Something that Rage used to generate some very petty scenes, and some very interesting texture popping.</p>

<p><img src="/post_images/Honors/Rage.jpg" title="'Rage'" ></p>

<p>The basic idea is that you create a massive texture file, in Rages case I believe they could be up to 128,000 x 128,000 pixels then just stream off the hard-drive (or disc) the information you need based on your position in the world.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Regardless of how much detail its texture might contain, you cannot display more texels than the screen has pixels.</p><footer><strong>Ben Garney</strong> <cite>Game Programming Gems 7 - Clipmapping</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The motivation is an old one, textures in the distance need not have as much detail in them as textures closer to the camera. But the two texture files might take up the same space on the GPU. So if we can stream in the amount of information when we need it we can save our-selfs a lot of memory.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thrid Year Group Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/group-project/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T21:55:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/group-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of our 3rd year in Uni, we had todo a group project. This was mainly an exercise in working with other disciplines and clients. A small group of us wanted to create our own game rather than pick from a selection of pre-produced briefs, so we pitched the game idea to the school, and managed to pickup some artists and audio people which we needed otherwise programmer art would have been a feature of our game.</p>

<p>A wee clip of one of the levels.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/50893418" width="500" height="375" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>The main idea is you have no direct control over the player, but instead can morph into different objects that in-turn move you in the environment. During our final pitches Disney saw our game and showed some interest, nothings come of it yet, but it was nice to have somebody outside of the Uni show some interest in the game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Faultline Terrain]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/02/01/faultline-terrain/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-01T19:58:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2012/02/01/faultline-terrain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an experiment of making procedural terrains using the faultline method.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/35978061" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>This first attempt was a little mental, the falloff for the fault size was quadratic and started very large. The result was these scary mountainous landscapes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lua Proof Of Concept]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/10/01/lua-proof-of-concept/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-01T19:58:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/10/01/lua-proof-of-concept</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of our group-project in uni, we looked into the possibility of using <a href="http://www.lua.org/" title="Lua">Lua</a> embedded with our framework, which was built upon <a href="http://www.libgosu.org/" title="Gosu">Gosu</a>.
There was a desire to use Lua to speed up iteration speeds, and also to include non-programmer types in the development of the game.
The actual embededing of Lua and <a href="http://www.rasterbar.com/products/luabind.html" title="LuaBind">Luabind</a> was relatively easy, the hard part came in the finicky little bits of LuaBind, and the difficulty of of debugging Lua scripts.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/31367803" width="500" height="375" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>We ended up ditching Lua for two reasons, its drain on my time, and the lack of interest (although initially shown) from the non-programmer's in the group to use it.</p>

<p>I’d like to revisit this some day though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGL Tardis]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/opengl-tardis/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T19:59:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/opengl-tardis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was my second year coursework for Graphics Programming. I was very disappointed in the module as a whole - I struggle to see the benefit of learning the fixed function pipeline any more, along with every feature of OpenGL that no longer exists. The module felt like it was put together by somebody who didn't care, and the claim that we would learn the theory of graphic programming turned out to be marketing speak, for learning next to nothing useful.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/22864220" width="500" height="370" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Disappointment of the module aside I was happy enough with outcome of my coursework, I created the models (but not the textures) in <a href="http://www.blender.org/" title="Blender">Blender</a>, and used <a href="http://chumbalum.swissquake.ch/" title="Milkshape">Milkshape</a> to import them (the only model loader I had at the time was a Milkshape one). Milkshape kept flipping the normals on me for some reason, the solution was rather mental, I turned them inside out in Blender and Milkshape flipped them back around.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
