<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: OpenGL | Phil Cooper-King]]></title>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/categories/opengl/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-10T16:26:54+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Phil CK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texture Importers]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/05/02/texture-importer/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T19:58:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/05/02/texture-importer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote these importers (Targa and Bitmap) for OpenGL (Well any API I guess), I originally wrote these for the PS2 because the importer we were given was such a pain to use.</p>

<p><img src="/post_images/SideProjects/texture_loader.png" title="'textures'" ></p>

<p>The Targa was interesting as it has quite a few features in the file spec, the fact you can orientate the image when storing to disc any way you want I found a little unnecessary. Code can be gotten here if you are interested, they are pretty much complete, although they don’t support RLE compression.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGL Tardis]]></title>
    <link href="http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/opengl-tardis/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T19:59:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://PhilCK.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/opengl-tardis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was my second year coursework for Graphics Programming. I was very disappointed in the module as a whole - I struggle to see the benefit of learning the fixed function pipeline any more, along with every feature of OpenGL that no longer exists. The module felt like it was put together by somebody who didn't care, and the claim that we would learn the theory of graphic programming turned out to be marketing speak, for learning next to nothing useful.</p>

<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/22864220" width="500" height="370" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Disappointment of the module aside I was happy enough with outcome of my coursework, I created the models (but not the textures) in <a href="http://www.blender.org/" title="Blender">Blender</a>, and used <a href="http://chumbalum.swissquake.ch/" title="Milkshape">Milkshape</a> to import them (the only model loader I had at the time was a Milkshape one). Milkshape kept flipping the normals on me for some reason, the solution was rather mental, I turned them inside out in Blender and Milkshape flipped them back around.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
